Gregory Read

<u>gregread@gmail.com</u> Jacksonville, FL 904-303-7334 <u>linkedin.com/in/gregoryread</u> <u>bravegeek.com</u>



Summary

I'm an experienced .NET developer who loves architecting elegant and pragmatic solutions to difficult business problems. I have a passion for delivering quality software using best-practices, not only during development, but through all steps of the life cycle. My desire to improve my team and advance their skills has led me into management where I can more readily share my knowledge. A love for learning helps me master best-practices and keeps my skills continuously sharp.

Computer Skills

Languages

- Proficient in C#, SQL
- Additional skill set in JavaScript, Powershell

Software

- Database: MS SQL Server, Azure SQL, Cosmos DB, Sybase
- Frameworks: .NET Framework, .NET Core, Web API, MVC, Entity Framework, Dapper, Angular, Linq, JSON
- Servers: IIS, SSIS, Graylog, IdentityServer, Redis, Linux, Solr, Elasticsearch
- Testing Tools: XUnit, Fixie, Shouldy, Moq, Autofixture, Artillery.io, JMeter

Cloud Technology

 Azure: Azure DevOps, Service Bus, App Service Plans, Web Jobs, App Host Plans, Logic Apps, Storage Accounts, Azure Maps, Application Insights, ARM Templates, Azure CLI, Virtual Networks, Network Security Groups, Key Vault, Virtual Machines

Productivity Tools

 Visual Studio 2019, Visual Studio Code, SQL Management Studio, Git, Postman, Chocolatey, ReSharper, DbUp

Experience

Software Development Manager, Step Up For Students

Jacksonville, FL- May 2019 - Present

Responsibilities

 Manage a department of 8 developers that were responsible for maintaining legacy applications, developing features, architecting new systems, and supporting production systems. Developers were spread across multiple product teams and were required to handle production support issues for their products.

Accomplishments

- Worked with our developers to repair strained relationships with other teams by taking more
 production support work from our Infrastructure team and training our QA team in more
 technical work. Being patient and consistently modeling the behavior I wanted to see helped
 our teams bond and improved our release cycles.
- Changed developer meetings from gripe sessions to productive collaborations by using a
 novel meeting style called "Lean Coffee". This agenda-less meeting allowed us to explore
 topics and easily share knowledge with an agreed time limit. Our exploration resulted in setting
 up a DevOps and Test Automation guild as well as implementing new tools like DbUp. These

- Lean Coffee meetings are so popular that we now use them across IT.
- Partnered with our Infrastructure team to implement zero-downtime releases to production.
 This involved modifying our release pipelines to play nicely with our load balancer. In addition to eliminating downtime, we saved over 40 man-hours a month babysitting late-night releases.
 Our production releases are now scheduled during the day and complete without drama.
- Mentored 4 junior developers with weekly one-on-one sessions to improve their skills and get them promoted. I helped find them assignments that would expose them to new technology and skills so they could continue their growth.
- Helped new developers get their projects running on our CI/CD infrastructure by partnering them with veteran developers. All of our products, from .Net to WordPress, flow through over 100 CI/CD pipelines so we can automate our releases.
- Used load testing to prepare for high traffic seasons (over 1 million requests per day). Load
 testing exposed weak points, e.g. missing database indexes, expensive queries, port
 exhaustion. It also gave us a good idea of how to scale our resources. Knowing that our key
 systems performed well under heavy load allowed our CIO to enjoy a worry-free holiday.
- Mentored students from the University of North Florida while they worked on their senior project. The seniors in computer science are assigned a software project to help a local non-profit. The software they develop provides a real boost to the overburdened staff. I also help them with side projects, job-seeking, and career advice.
- Currently working on storing secrets in Azure Key Vault. This will allow us to easily rotate
 sensitive keys while keeping them from being stored in the clear. Partnering with Infrastructure
 and Security has been the key ingredient in getting this started.

Technologies used

Azure DevOps, Azure SQL, Logic Apps, Artillery.io

Senior Software Developer, Step Up For Students

Jacksonville, FL— Jul 2016 - May 2019

Responsibilities

- Lead a team of 5 developers to modernize our largest scholarship's intake process. This application is responsible for over 150,00 students applying for scholarships.
- Modernization included moving all new development to Azure, changing our technology stack from Web Forms to Angular, and implementing OAuth2 for security.

Accomplishments

- Created a production Graylog server in Azure and integrated authentication with our AD. Our Graylog server handles over 40 million messages a month.
- Increased log visibility by moving logging in legacy applications from Sql Server to Graylog.
 This reduced the load on the database and enabled non-developers to search our logs for issues. More visibility allowed us faster troubleshooting of production issues.
- Reduced our cloud spending by partnering with our Infrastructure team to move our Azure
 resources to a lower cost Dev/Test subscription. Further reduced costs by using Redis to
 cache expensive calls to Cosmos DB saving us over \$100 a month. Our success with Redis
 prompted us to use it in other places to improve performance.
- Reduced code defects by writing unit tests and taught other developers unit testing principles. We now have over 1,200 unit tests covering our most critical business logic, our covered code never fails regression testing.
- Improved release cycles by creating a Feature Switch library to allow us to tackle large features that spanned multiple sprints.
- Increased team efficiency by writing internal tools to speed our database setups and easily

create clients and scopes in IdentityServer

Technologies used

Web API, MVC, .Net Core, .Net Framework, Entity Framework, Dapper, IdentityServer, Angular, Graylog, XUnit, Fixie, Dependency Injection, Polly, AutoMapper, Linux, Azure DevOps, Cosmos DB, Azure SQL, ServiceBus, Redis, ARM Templates, App Services, WebJobs

Senior Developer, ATP Tour Inc.

Ponte Vedra Beach, FL— Jan 2011 - Jul 2016

Responsibilities

- Ensure the success of our \$40 million dollar data distribution contract by creating technical tools and then training officials and tournament personnel.
- Support the atptour.com public website so it performs under heavy load. Create feeds from historical data to power a website upgrade.

Accomplishments

- Gave new insights into historical data by building a new web service layer for the atptour.com
 website. SSIS was used to ETL historical tennis data from Sybase to a MS SQL data
 warehouse. I used Web API to expose the data via JSON, http headers were used to
 determine language, and caching was configured at the controller level.
- Decreased the load on our origin servers by using HTTP cache-control headers so the CDN could base its TTL rules on the max-age. I used the IIS URL Rewrite Module and Outbound rules to accomplish this. This allowed us to quickly adjust our TTLs for different tournaments by simply changing the config file.
- Eliminated cache inconsistencies across origin servers by migrating the Sitecore CMS indexes from Lucene to a SolrCloud implementation that utilized a ZooKeeper ensemble.
- Improved user experience by creating a module in Sitecore to catch unresolved URLs and determine if they needed to redirect to current players or tournaments. I hooked into the Sitecore processing pipeline to intercept these URLs just before they directed to a 404.
- Improved our data accuracy (and partner happiness) by developing a tracking system to
 monitor umpire scoring accuracy and data loss. This tracking system gave real-time access to
 officials and greatly improved our Data Distribution product. I had to work closely with umpires
 and management to develop the correct metrics.
- Partnered with umpires and officials to improve our data collection software and process.
 Personnel at tournaments felt included in decisions because their feedback directly affected the tools they used.
- Setup a Jenkins server to automate the build and deployment for .Net projects. I used Gulp to automate the build, run unit tests, increment the version, and deploy artifacts.

Technologies used

Asp.Net, Web API, .Net Framework, Entity Framework, SQL Server, SSIS, IIS, Solr, ZooKeeper, Linux, Jenkins, Dependency Injection, NUnit, AutoMapper, CDN

Programmer/Analyst, Jacksonville Jaguars

Jacksonville, FL— May 2000 - Dec 2010

Responsibilities

 Support the Scouting department and automate tasks to give Scouts more time to write evaluations.

Accomplishments

Reduced the setup time for draft meetings from days to hours by creating a web based draft

- board using ASP.NET and jQuery to replace an antiquated system of paper labels and magnets.
- Improved Scouts' efficiency by modernizing our scouting application. I used .Net to give a
 unified interface by combining the functionality of separate apps that were written in J++, VB6,
 Delphi, and MS Access.
- Developed an encryption and audit solution for PCI Compliance using MS SQL 2005.

Technologies used

Asp.Net, .Net Framework, NHibernate, SQL Server, SSRS, IIS

Technical Analyst, First Union National Bank

Jacksonville, FL— Aug 1995 - May 2000

Responsibilities

 Create a tool to interface with a mainframe to give different departments a simple means to monitor accounts.

Accomplishments

- Allowed technicians to quickly search and reference accounts on a legacy Tandem system using MS Access and SQL server.
- Improved back office efficiency by moving paper-based processes to MS Access.

Education

Florida State University

B.S., Physics— 1999

Continuing Education

Azure Fundamentals

(AZ-900) - Microsoft Certification ID: 990131728

CEM Courses

sponsored by Step Up for Students - Cognitive and Emotional Management is your ability to recognize and understand emotions in yourself and others.

- CEM Skills a Basic Understanding
- How to Overcome Conflict and Adversity
- Leading with Your Strengths
- How to Write Effective Written Feedback

Passions and Hobbies

Service work

- Mentor for <u>Senior Projects</u> in the School of Computing at the University of North Florida
- Volunteer at The Pulse Ministries

Technology

• F#, Kubernetes, JavaScript game programming

Exercise

Running, backpacking, scuba diving